Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, January 23rd, 2024.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight we are talking about the games of Magfest 2024.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we were away at the Magfest, and we came home.
Speaker 1: Oh right, I forgot about the weird thing that happened with the smelly bits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so a package showed up at the door, and there were several packages that we were expecting that we got, and that was just fine, they weren't urgent.
Speaker 0: And one package, which was addressed to us, to our house, with our correct address on it, but we were not expecting this package.
Speaker 0: We just opened it, it was addressed to us, and inside this package were between one, and I'd estimate $3,000 worth at retail price, of semi-luxury perfumes, clearly intended for a retail store, because it included the testers as well.
Speaker 1: See, now if you had said almost anything else, I would have been less surprised.
Speaker 1: That was a surprising thing to be in that box, but my immediate thoughts were, this feels like one of those complex scams that happens via companies like Amazon.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a couple scams, right?
Speaker 0: One scam is when something shows up at your house you didn't buy, and what really happened is, somebody else bought it, and they just wanted their Amazon account to say that they bought it, so that they could write a verified review of it, without actually, right?
Speaker 0: And the second kind of scam, which is illegal in the United States, is someone sends you something, and then, ha ha, you kept it, you didn't send it back, and they try to charge you for it, which is flat out illegal, that's clear, because people tried that scam.
Speaker 1: I want to say, the US had to pass a very specific law about that exact scam, because it got so common.
Speaker 0: That exact scam has been shut down.
Speaker 0: You don't have to worry about that scam if you're in the United States.
Speaker 0: If someone sends you something addressed to you, it's yours, that's effectively considered a gift.
Speaker 1: So whatever's going on here, irrespective of morals, ethics, or what you might do, you're under no obligation to give that to anyone.
Speaker 0: That's, well, no, what's going on here is quite, is a legally ambiguous situation.
Speaker 0: What has happened is this package, which was addressed to us, has a second shipping label, and that second shipping label is to a drug store in Canada.
Speaker 1: Ooh, reused box.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: A reused box, possibly?
Speaker 0: No, I think what happened is both labels, the one addressed to us, and the one addressed to the drug store in Canada, both have the same return address, which is a warehouse in North Carolina that deals in this kind of merchandise.
Speaker 0: So clearly what happened is someone packaged this up and slapped a label on it, so it went to Canada, and somehow, accidentally, a second label was slapped onto it for us, right, at the warehouse.
Speaker 0: And then, I don't know which carrier the other label goes to, because it doesn't have a carrier named on it, it doesn't say, like, FedEx or anything, it must be some international carrier, or USPS, or who knows, but it doesn't have a USPS logo, it just has the Canadian address.
Speaker 0: And so the other label, the one with our address, says UPS.
Speaker 0: It's clearly a UPS label.
Speaker 0: So, what happened, obviously, is that once it had both labels on it, a UPS courier had it, scanned our label, and thus, it ended up at our house.
Speaker 1: Yup, I guess 50/50 shot which label gets scanned.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know, I don't even know if the other label is UPS, but our label is actually kind of a messed up label, that's like all fucked up printed, but, and the other label is clear as day, but ours is on top, and the other label was on the side.
Speaker 0: So, but I guess once it's in the hands of UPS, they're gonna scan the UPS label only, right?
Speaker 0: And the other label, if it is not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So, that label got scanned, therefore the package came to us.
Speaker 0: So, I probably could just sell all this merch somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: And collect some money, obviously it would be less than the actual retail price, but regardless, not a bad haul for free, right?
Speaker 0: However, I'm like, well, let me make sure, right, I'll do a good faith effort, 'cause I don't, you know, if I just go on eBay and I start selling testers, that's gonna look real shady.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's exactly the kind of account that would hit someone with the triangulation scam.
Speaker 0: I don't wanna mess up my eBay account.
Speaker 0: that's from the 90s, anyway.
Speaker 0: So, I called, right, first, the warehouse.
Speaker 0: Big, it was very difficult to communicate with the warehouse, right?
Speaker 0: Their phone menu obviously didn't have anything that could deal with this.
Speaker 0: I was eventually routed to a voicemail by talking to some other people who didn't really, it wasn't their job to deal with it, like the security person at the warehouse or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I left a voicemail with a person who has not called me back.
Speaker 0: And then, I called the Canadian drugstore.
Speaker 0: It was very difficult to get to a human being at the Canadian drugstore, but I did get to the manager of the Canadian drugstore in distant Alberta.
Speaker 0: It's really fucking far away.
Speaker 0: It's like hours northwest of Edmonton on the border with BC.
Speaker 0: It's way out there.
Speaker 1: See, but this is the trickiest part.
Speaker 1: If you're in a situation like this where someone else messed up, there is an amount of effort that a reasonable person is willing to go through before it just becomes a waste of time and it's not worth the effort to try.
Speaker 0: Most people would have done zero effort, right?
Speaker 0: I did 1000x more effort than most people.
Speaker 0: So I called the Canadian drugstore and I'm like, "Hey, this was supposed to come to you.
Speaker 0: It was coming from North Carolina.
Speaker 0: I have it.
Speaker 0: If you're expecting it, it's probably not going to show up and you shouldn't pay for
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: And they said, "All right.
Speaker 0: Thanks.".
Speaker 0: You know, they were Canadian and friendly and they were intelligent and knew what was up.
Speaker 0: And they told, they got their accounting person, I guess, to not pay for it, right?
Speaker 0: And they told me to call UPS to see what could be done there.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: I'll call UPS since I don't know what the other carrier
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 0: So UPS was difficult to talk to because their phone system also doesn't have anything to handle this particular scenario, right?
Speaker 0: If your scenario is outside the bounds of the options available, what are you going to do, right?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: But eventually, and even UPS actually blocked the push zero to talk to human.
Speaker 0: They're like,
Speaker 0: "Whoa.".
Speaker 0: So, but I was able to get a UPS human who then I did the like, you know, you call me back later option, right?
Speaker 0: And they notified another UPS human who was like a regional person of some kind, dispatch type job.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly how they work.
Speaker 0: And that person called me and they were very intelligent and understood the scenario.
Speaker 0: And I explained to them everything.
Speaker 0: And they said,
Speaker 0: "Okay.".
Speaker 0: Most people wouldn't have called or said anything, right?
Speaker 0: But they also said that they will try to contact the warehouse, which I failed to do.
Speaker 0: So I assume that they will also fail because we opened it, which they didn't blame me for opening it.
Speaker 0: Like any reasonable person would open a package addressed to them, right?
Speaker 1: I want to say there's some legal protection that even if you were not expecting a package.
Speaker 0: It's addressed to me.
Speaker 1: You have a right to open it if it is addressed to you.
Speaker 1: Full stop.
Speaker 0: But it has the UPS as far as they're concerned.
Speaker 0: It was a package from the warehouse to us that was successfully delivered because that tracking number has them as the return address and us as the destination.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's a big heavy box and I'm not paying to ship it anywhere.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: F that.
Speaker 0: And so they're like, listen, you opened it.
Speaker 0: And therefore, the only way that we can take it and send it back where it came from is if they put a claim on it as damaged because it was opened.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, well, I mean, I could just close it and they wouldn't even know it was damaged.
Speaker 0: They're like, no, can't do that.
Speaker 0: He needs to convince the warehouse people to make a claim to have it sent back to them.
Speaker 0: And I guess otherwise, question mark means.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure if there is not rapid follow up by these people, no one's going to contact you again.
Speaker 1: And unless you take extraordinary efforts, that's just your perfume.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: And the only thing that I can see happening that would not be the scenario you just described is the very small chance that when the drugstore decides not to pay, that then the warehouse would suddenly take notice.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's the only chance I could see of this going in a different direction is if the warehouse takes notice after the drugstore doesn't pay and the drugstore knows right.
Speaker 0: That's my phone number.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I left the voicemail at the warehouse.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if they some that's the only if.
Speaker 0: that if that doesn't trigger a fixing of the situation, then I just got mailed a bunch of retail merchandise that we can either use, keep, share and or sell, which ain't bad.
Speaker 0: I could trade this for like a television probably.
Speaker 1: If I were a betting man, I would bet that you're going to get to keep that perfume and never no one's ever going to contact you.
Speaker 0: I'm like 75 percent sure we're just going to sell this and put it in our bank account is what we don't see.
Speaker 1: And a small number of those vials are going to end up staying in your home is my purse.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if they smell good.
Speaker 0: I haven't opened any right.
Speaker 0: I mean, I find that they are their luxury brands such as Gucci and Marc Jacobs and whatever.
Speaker 1: In my in my personal experience, I have found that I do not like the scent of most extremely expensive perfumes, but I like the scent of much cheaper perfumes.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I actually you know, the thing is that I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't not really sure.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The thing is, every perfume I smell that's from like that's like a brand perfume.
Speaker 0: They all smell like perfume section at the department store.
Speaker 0: I can't tell the difference between them very much.
Speaker 0: I have to have in order for me to tell the difference.
Speaker 0: I have to have like two next to each other where I can smell one and then smell the other one immediately.
Speaker 0: And then I go, ah, I sell the difference.
Speaker 0: But if you just spray one of them at me, it doesn't matter which one.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to be like, smells like department store.
Speaker 1: There are.
Speaker 1: But I have there.
Speaker 1: I have a memory.
Speaker 1: I can differentiate very specifically.
Speaker 1: Stetson just because I wore that when I was like middle school and high school.
Speaker 1: And then I stopped because I grew up.
Speaker 1: I'm an adult.
Speaker 1: But Stetson has a very distinct smell that I will pick out of a crowd in a department store.
Speaker 1: I can pick out Stetson from the other perfumes just like in the wall of smell.
Speaker 1: I can pick out only the category that I would say I only smell when you're at a high school function of some kind.
Speaker 1: And all the boys are wearing generic cologne.
Speaker 1: I can pick out that generic cologne smell and all my badger beard oil smell very different.
Speaker 1: But that's not really perfume.
Speaker 0: The only perfume memory I have is that I have a memory that I smelled Chanel number five, which is like the most famous perfume, I guess.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Even I know it and that I thought it smelled good.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I don't remember what the fuck it smelled like.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it actually smells good.
Speaker 0: I just have a memory of it smelling good.
Speaker 0: I bet the way the human brain works, if you sprayed some, I wouldn't and I covered the bottle.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't know what the fuck it was.
Speaker 0: I might even think it smells nasty right now.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I bet if you smelled it again, it would trigger that memory and you would be like, oh, shit, that's Chanel number five.
Speaker 1: And it'd be weird that you remember that.
Speaker 0: It's possible, but I have no clue.
Speaker 0: I just have a memory of smelling it at some point.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of knowing that that's what I was smelling, showing that, wow, that actually does smell good.
Speaker 0: That's no wonder.
Speaker 0: it's famous.
Speaker 1: Smells are some of the most powerful triggers to recall an engram from human memory, like more so than almost any other thing.
Speaker 0: This is not a memory.
Speaker 0: This is something I heard elsewhere.
Speaker 0: is that the cologne that Napoleon wore is apparently still available.
Speaker 0: Like you can just buy it and it's not that expensive relative to perfumes and that it's also possibly smells good.
Speaker 0: And now I am curious to smell that.
Speaker 1: I'm a little curious too, but if you ask me in a vacuum, would you like to smell the way Napoleon smelled?
Speaker 1: My answer would be a qualified, I need to know more about what Napoleon smelled like.
Speaker 0: That's exactly.
Speaker 0: I want to know more about what Napoleon smelled like.
Speaker 0: And apparently you can, you can.
Speaker 0: Now here's the real double factor.
Speaker 0: We need it.
Speaker 0: We know the third thing to go with this.
Speaker 0: Try factor, but the two factor would be to smell where the Napoleon cologne and drink the Kings pee at the same time.
Speaker 1: We just need a third thing.
Speaker 1: And also that might be the most across all we've ever made on geek nights.
Speaker 1: If we had eight things, it would be perfect.
Speaker 1: So you got turned French.
Speaker 0: You would just suddenly a duck bill.
Speaker 1: So you got any news?
Speaker 0: Uh, there's a couple of news.
Speaker 0: is so?
Speaker 0: this game came out called pal world, which is made by a developer called pocket pair.
Speaker 0: Apparently they originally tried to make a game called craft opiate.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that still exists, but this game, the pal world seems to be very similar to their craft opiate.
Speaker 0: It's one of those, you know, um, you know, uh, sort of survival action adventure games that has, you know, real time 3d third person combats and also building factories like satisfactory, but also farming and survival, you know, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But they differentiated themselves with this power world game by basically ripping off Pokemon, right?
Speaker 0: It's based.
Speaker 0: You want to run the factory?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You capture monsters and put them to slave labor in your factory.
Speaker 0: You can kill monsters and eat them.
Speaker 0: Monsters can eat other monsters.
Speaker 0: Monsters can just have fucking guns, right?
Speaker 0: It's just like, yeah, we're going to do all the things with our monsters that definitely aren't Pokemon that you couldn't allow.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to do with Pokemon.
Speaker 0: And this game is now the number one game on steam, period.
Speaker 0: Counterstrike, Dota, they're behind this game as of now, and it's still early access and it just came out.
Speaker 1: It sold 6 million copies in the first four days it was live.
Speaker 1: And what's weird, I don't think I know a single human who is playing it or wants to play it.
Speaker 0: Well, it sort of became a thing while we were at magfest.
Speaker 0: It's that recent, but the, you can also there, you can play four player co-op, but I think you can also like run your own server to get 32 people together or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the interesting thing about this game is that people have modded in surprise, actual Pokemon right into this game.
Speaker 0: They just, you know, haha, obviously the company can't sell Pokemon, but we can just put Pokemon in there and now it's actual Pikachu with a gun.
Speaker 1: Like in the old days you could take Doom and just put Mickey Mouse in a wad and there he is.
Speaker 0: Well, you could if it was, legally at least.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could do it illegally back then.
Speaker 1: It's not Doom's fault that I made a custom wad with Mickey Mouse.
Speaker 0: So Nintendo, of course, has not failed to notice this, especially since the PALworld company is a Japanese company, the developer and publisher.
Speaker 0: And so the people who are making, they're not going after the PALworld company because, you know, they have differentiated their monsters enough and that they can't be gone after.
Speaker 1: I don't think Nintendo has anything on the PALworld company unless the company enforces- If you're making the official Pokemon mods, Nintendo is going after them unsurprisingly.
Speaker 0: So I suggest A) If you want to do some official Pokemon mods on your PALworld server, get them while they're hot.
Speaker 0: 2) If you're making these mods, stop releasing them publicly.
Speaker 0: Put them on some shady website Nintendo will never find.
Speaker 0: And 3) I don't know if this game is actually any good.
Speaker 1: I read some reviews of this game from people I trust and the reviews all said it's empty and hollow and it feels like the kind of game that NFT people would make.
Speaker 0: Like it's a nothing game.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it even one second, I've just seen video footage, but it seems like it's sort of a cookie cutter kind of deal, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of trying to beat everything to everybody.
Speaker 0: But hey, at least it doesn't seem like it has microtransactions though, right?
Speaker 1: At least I can tell.
Speaker 1: It's an empty, soulless, according to a bunch of reviewers, like I have not played it, empty soulless open world with some survival and crafting stuff to do if you want.
Speaker 0: It is only $27 in early access, so that's not really unreasonable, especially if there's no microtransaction bullshit and you can run your own server.
Speaker 1: But what's interesting, like the real interesting part about this, is the online reaction.
Speaker 1: There's corners of the internet that the company has said their developers are getting tons of death threats, mostly from people who are...
Speaker 0: I have to read this.
Speaker 1: There's an IGN article about it.
Speaker 1: Palworld devs say they've received death threats amid their Pokemon ripoff claims.
Speaker 1: They've also said they're receiving death threats.
Speaker 0: So I guess there's a handful of Poke Ultra fans probably in Japan.
Speaker 1: Pokemon fans are going after this company, but also people are going after this company claiming that they just used AI to make the art, and they're mad about the fact that AI is involved, which...
Speaker 0: I don't think that that's the case.
Speaker 1: It may or may not be true, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's possible, but...
Speaker 1: These character designs are indistinguishable from any generic "I need to make a bunch of monsters" characters.
Speaker 1: The IGN article I read made a good point.
Speaker 1: If Digimon came out today, the people who are sending death threats to this company claiming they're using AI would be sending death threats to Digimon because Digimon looked like they were made by an AI.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, none of these creatures, you know, it's like, yeah, they look like someone made a bunch of, you know, Pokemon imitations that are different enough to avoid lawsuits, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, but none of them are like particularly inspiring or charming or like you want to have a figure of one of them or, you know, merchandise or anything.
Speaker 0: But I guess people who play this game might become attached to some of these characters, right?
Speaker 0: Even though, you know, who gives a shit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's really fascinating.
Speaker 1: There's tons of these articles talking about people who either are making shit up saying that this company used AI or are trying to prove that they're using AI.
Speaker 1: And it seems like it's almost become a proxy for a subset of the internet for people who are mad about AI in general and this is just the company they're going after.
Speaker 0: Seems like one story that got republished on every single website that, you know, is an AI generated website that republishes news.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's a weird Reddit thread about it too, but I read all these articles and I can't find anything that appears that this company did anything wrong.
Speaker 1: So I feel like what might really just be happening is a new game came out, it's really popular and people seem to get mad whenever something's popular and get weird about it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They're digging out like tweets the CEO made a long time ago talking about, "Hey, what if I used AI to generate
Speaker 1: Pokemon?".
Speaker 1: But those might also themselves be fake tweets and there's no links to them.
Speaker 0: It's the old soldier jumping in front of the whatever meme, right?
Speaker 0: Well, weird nerds.
Speaker 0: In other minor news, right, Polygon has an article about this study, right?
Speaker 0: I can't actually find the data from the study that they're talking about.
Speaker 0: It might have just been like a study they did themselves.
Speaker 0: Polygon surveyed more than 4,000 Americans over the age of 18 about their anime consumption habits.
Speaker 0: So basically this is the study and they haven't published their raw data that I can find, but they did the study themselves.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: And this is just their report on it.
Speaker 0: And basically their study is that, hey, yes indeed what you thought anime is way more popular than it appears to be.
Speaker 0: And you can read all these numbers yourself because obviously we're going to put the link here on our website and in our notes and everything like that.
Speaker 1: You always like to say where on one hand, duh, obviously I knew this, but at the other hand, there's a difference between feeling like you know something and having data to show it.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the thing is, I've been saying this for a while and I'm more sure of it every day, is that there is a huge, I guess, I had the right word for it and I forgot the right word, but there is a huge separation between how popular we think a thing is or how popular a thing is perceived to be and how popular a thing actually is.
Speaker 1: Well, case in point, people who are fans of, I don't know, random generic TV sitcom, it's not like, there might be hundreds of millions of people watching that sitcom.
Speaker 1: How many of them are going to go to a convention about that sitcom or even about sitcoms or even think to mention it to people in most conversations?
Speaker 1: Like it doesn't come up.
Speaker 0: So the image of an anime fan is- There are things which are popular but do not appear to be popular because there is no talk about them either amongst the people or amongst the media, right?
Speaker 0: There are things that are unpopular that appear to be big and popular because like they're in the movie theater and someone's doing a promo circuit and a lot of money is being pumped into it.
Speaker 1: Marvel comic books.
Speaker 0: There are ads and there are, you know, astroturfs and it seems like it's a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you could have something where like one person tweets about a thing and then maybe there's five people who are in agreement.
Speaker 0: And then someone does a news story on it and then every news outlet copies that news story and now what was just five people seems like a fad and a trend and then people get in on it.
Speaker 0: But how many people were ever actually in on it, right?
Speaker 0: That kind of thing can happen.
Speaker 1: That whole Fortnite thing.
Speaker 1: Fortnite made a change and if you looked at the internet, you would believe that everyone who plays Fortnite is up in arms and they're going to quit the game.
Speaker 1: And then when all the people who said they quit were quit, Fortnite was like, yeah, that was basically zero people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So this is- and sometimes it's actually true.
Speaker 0: Think that seems unpopular is unpopular.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, you know, and think that seems popular is popular, right?
Speaker 1: But anime has definitely been- It's just mainstream, generically popular.
Speaker 1: There are definitely tons of people who watch a lot of anime and would never think to even mention that fact to other people.
Speaker 0: So I think that's just something we had to be aware of is the perception of popularity and the truth of popularity are strongly disconnected in many ways.
Speaker 1: In one last little bit of news, this has been making the rounds for a while, but I just wanted to highlight it because this is one example that's very specific.
Speaker 1: There's a board game called Kelp.
Speaker 1: Looks like a cute game.
Speaker 1: I don't have any strong opinion on it.
Speaker 1: I haven't read the rules.
Speaker 0: It was on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: I saw it, but I wasn't interested.
Speaker 1: And because it's a small Kickstarter, it is only available via that Kickstarter or the pledge manager related to the Kickstarting on Kickstarter.
Speaker 1: Like, there's nowhere else to buy it unless you go to the secondary market and buy it from someone who already bought it from that pledge manager from the original Kickstarter.
Speaker 0: But the Kickstarter hasn't printed and shipped yet, so you couldn't buy-.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: So, despite the game having not actually been delivered to people yet, it appeared on Amazon and eBay and tons of other dodgy websites and got really popular.
Speaker 1: And the people who made it put out a press release saying, and I'm quoting, "At the moment, Kelp can only be purchased on our pledge manager.
Speaker 1: We have discovered counterfeit copies of Kelp on platforms like Amazon, eBay, Frugal,
Speaker 1: worldwide.".
Speaker 1: And it goes on to detail everything they know about this situation.
Speaker 1: And this is not the first.
Speaker 1: This is not going to be the last.
Speaker 1: This is going to be a problem that's going to escalate rapidly.
Speaker 1: Because board games like this tend to get printed in a very small number of facilities around the world.
Speaker 1: And it's very easy for anyone involved in that process to just print more or just look at images and recreate a shitty version of the game and then print it at a similar kind of facility.
Speaker 1: There's no checks on this stuff.
Speaker 1: It's not like every factory does a full copyright check of every random job that gets sent to them.
Speaker 0: This has been a problem for decades now.
Speaker 0: And this is the reason the U.S.
Speaker 0: has intellectual property law is because they basically created a regime whereby you can have a job where you designed a thing.
Speaker 0: And you thought of the thing, the knowledge work.
Speaker 0: And you wrote a SOG.
Speaker 0: And that knowledge work gets financially rewarded in capitalism.
Speaker 0: And so when you buy an Apple product, what does it always say?
Speaker 0: Designed in California, manufactured in other country.
Speaker 0: Every single Apple product has a little notice in there that says exactly those words.
Speaker 0: And Apple is reaping most of the profits because they designed it.
Speaker 0: But in the real world, there is no.
Speaker 0: if there were no governments, you know, make enforcing laws that made those things happen on purpose.
Speaker 0: People who design things would see no return on their work.
Speaker 0: Only people who manufacture things are able to see a return because they're the ones who produce the goods.
Speaker 1: The whoever controls the thing.
Speaker 1: that is scarce about something is the only person who can make money without laws, regulations and society backing up the rest of that process.
Speaker 0: Your only hope as a person who designs a thing, a knowledge worker would be to keep your knowledge hidden until the very last minute.
Speaker 0: And you would go to a factory and say, hey, factory, I have a board game.
Speaker 0: It's guaranteed to be a big seller.
Speaker 0: You've seen my other games.
Speaker 0: They were big sellers.
Speaker 0: I will give you the files for this board game.
Speaker 0: They have never been exposed to the outside world except on my secure enclave in exchange for this pile of money, one shot pile of money.
Speaker 0: And then once those files are out, the whole world is now able to produce your game infinitely and you will not be able to see any monies for it.
Speaker 0: That is what it would be like if for people who design things, if there were no governments enforcing any kind of law and capitalism still exists.
Speaker 1: What's specifically happening here is that we've hit a point where this would happen off and on because there's various ways to do it.
Speaker 1: But nowadays, partly because there's print and plays.
Speaker 1: People will post screenshots and videos of a board game before it comes out.
Speaker 1: People can get images or guess at the parts they can't see.
Speaker 1: These aren't even just like the factory, like someone took the factory files and printed more.
Speaker 1: Some of these counterfeits are like badly put together.
Speaker 1: They have errors.
Speaker 1: They were clearly made by hand by people who are dedicated to finding board games they can make black market copies of and just making them.
Speaker 1: Like there's all these screenshots of the absolute garbage that has showed up in the mail of people who bought the game who didn't even think they were pirating.
Speaker 1: They thought they were buying the game legitimately.
Speaker 1: They weren't even trying to pirate.
Speaker 0: We've had lots of counterfeit board games for years now, but this is a new one in that the game isn't even out yet.
Speaker 0: That's what makes this one a different situation.
Speaker 0: Somehow the files were recreated or stolen or hoisted in some fashion, leaked at a factory or stolen from the Kickstarter or somehow.
Speaker 0: Who knows if the counterfeit game is even playable, but they're printing it and selling it regardless.
Speaker 1: But I guess be ready.
Speaker 1: This is the tiniest tip of an iceberg that's about to crash across the entire tabletop world except for those games that have minis for now.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that this is going to scare people who make tabletop games into doing things a bit differently.
Speaker 1: Can't do print and plays.
Speaker 1: You definitely can't let anyone have enough assets to make your game in tabletop simulator.
Speaker 0: Well, that's one person suggested that maybe what happened is since they had like a tabletop simulator demo that someone might have gone and taken the assets from the tabletop simulator and use that to create the counterfeit.
Speaker 1: If a game exists in tabletop simulator, which itself is a dubious application in terms of legality and ethical use of other people's intellectual property, we sidestep all that even if somehow tabletop simulator was super secure.
Speaker 1: Analog whole, someone could play the game, take screenshots and print their shitty counterfeit.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: We actually have two very similar things of the day in that two rare things have happened recently in ice hockey.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: In the game of ice hockey, in the NHL, right?
Speaker 0: Weird things happen in other leagues besides the NHL on a somewhat regular basis.
Speaker 0: I'd say at least a few times a month maybe during hockey season, but in the NHL, if there are things that basically never happen that could theoretically happen and two of them happened on the same day, days apart.
Speaker 0: And it's like, these are extremely, it's like two cocoa beans together.
Speaker 1: Mine is from the end of last year.
Speaker 1: It's not immediate.
Speaker 1: It's just been in my queue.
Speaker 1: December 16th, I think was this one.
Speaker 1: So mine is there's a rule.
Speaker 0: I didn't hear December.
Speaker 0: I didn't hear about it until.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't hear about it until like a week ago when I saw this.
Speaker 0: That's why I thought they were days apart is because even I didn't hear about it and I read everything.
Speaker 1: So the last time I remember this happening and when I learned this was a rule was in the year 1997 when Patrick Waugh violated this rule.
Speaker 1: And I remember it because it was a big deal.
Speaker 1: When the ref flew the whistle, Patrick Waugh looks at him like, "What?
Speaker 0: What'd I
Speaker 0: do?".
Speaker 1: And nobody, like nobody knew this was a rule.
Speaker 1: Like players didn't know it was a rule.
Speaker 0: Refs did.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It didn't happen again until once in 2006.
Speaker 1: And now in 2023, it happened for a third time.
Speaker 1: And the rule is if you're a goalie in the NHL, you can play the puck anywhere except outside, behind the net in the two corners.
Speaker 1: You can just play the puck, but you can not cross the center line with the puck.
Speaker 1: That is a penalty.
Speaker 0: You can skate over the center line, but you can't touch the puck while you're over the center line.
Speaker 1: You can't control the puck.
Speaker 0: And you can't touch the puck in the back corners outside the trapezoid since they added the trapezoid rule.
Speaker 0: But anywhere else, either in the trapezoid or in your crease or in the zone on your half of the ice or even in the neutral zone on your half of the neutral zone, the goalie can play the puck.
Speaker 1: So when Patrick Wong got the penalty, he was just dicking around and being funny in a game that didn't matter, like they'd already won.
Speaker 1: And he just skates out and he's skating forward with the puck and it was kind of funny.
Speaker 1: But in this case, just watch the video, you'll see how it went down.
Speaker 1: But you might think it's understandable that people wouldn't know about this rule because there is no situation anyone could imagine in the modern NHL where a goalie would on purpose want to be over there where the puck is in play.
Speaker 1: But this is a long-standing rule because in old-timey hockey, the reason this is a rule is because goalies did it all the time and they kept getting hurt.
Speaker 1: And the NHL banned them playing on the other side of the red line to prevent them from getting hurt because they kept doing it.
Speaker 1: So what's your weird hockey thing?
Speaker 0: So in the game of ice hockey, if a team gets a penalty, the ref raises their hand and when the penalized team has control of the puck or basically touches the puck at all, right, they blow the whistle and say, "Hey, we're going to stop playing because we've got to put one of your players in the
Speaker 0: box.".
Speaker 0: But let's say rim's team gets a penalty and team Scott still has the puck.
Speaker 0: Well, we're going to raise our hand to let you know that a penalty has been called.
Speaker 0: But we're not going to stop you from playing because, well, the team that has the puck didn't do anything wrong, right?
Speaker 0: What if they score a goal right now and we don't want to stop them prematurely?
Speaker 1: They got the same rule in the NHL if someone's injured on the ice unless they're grievously injured where they won't stop play until the team that has the puck in the offensive zone no longer has the puck.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, because otherwise, you know, you could just commit a penalty on purpose to stop my team from scoring a goal.
Speaker 0: Oh, what's his name?
Speaker 1: There's that one guy who did that over and over and over again, like 40, 50 years ago, and the NHL made a rule about it right like the next season.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So obviously you can't have that penalizing on purpose to stop play to stop goals.
Speaker 0: So as long as you're not the team that was penalized, if you're touching the puck, you keep playing.
Speaker 0: And you know in that situation that if the other team touches the puck, the whistle will blow immediately.
Speaker 0: So you don't need a goalie anymore.
Speaker 0: So it's called a delayed penalty.
Speaker 0: And when that happens, usually your goalie will get off the ice to bring out another player skater and try to score and try to keep the puck away from the other team.
Speaker 0: And that's a good situation for you.
Speaker 0: You're basically extending your power play with a delayed penalty.
Speaker 0: Now, the situation is.
Speaker 0: it's like, well, your net is empty then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, yeah, but how is it going to go?
Speaker 0: We're not in trouble here.
Speaker 0: We're not going to get scored on because if they touch the puck, this play stops immediately.
Speaker 0: They cannot score on that.
Speaker 0: But you can accidentally put the puck in your own net in that situation, in which case it would be a goal.
Speaker 0: And I've known that.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows that.
Speaker 0: That's not an unknown mystery.
Speaker 1: It is the most common cause of own goals in the NHL is this exact situation.
Speaker 1: But own goals aren't that common.
Speaker 0: But it almost never happens, basically.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't remember it.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it did happen.
Speaker 0: This isn't the first time.
Speaker 0: But I don't remember it ever happening.
Speaker 0: I have never seen it with my own eyes.
Speaker 1: When I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I have never seen it with my own eyes at an NHL game.
Speaker 0: And of course it happened.
Speaker 0: The Penguins embarrassingly lost big with an own goal themselves in exactly this fashion.
Speaker 0: It was disgraceful.
Speaker 1: It's so funny.
Speaker 0: And it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: Just score on yourself.
Speaker 0: Congrats.
Speaker 1: In the moment, the Geek Nights Book Club book is the night of short walk on girl.
Speaker 1: I imagine we will do this Book Club episode mid-February.
Speaker 0: Alright, I have to start reading that again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm going to go on a trip next week.
Speaker 1: And it's a ski trip.
Speaker 1: So there's one, no Geek Nights next week.
Speaker 1: But two, I will have a lot of downtime to quietly read before I fall asleep between skiing.
Speaker 1: Because I'm the kind of skier.
Speaker 1: I'm on the first chair and I'm on the last chair.
Speaker 1: And I'm basically skiing as much as possible the entire time.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're traveling to, you know, I don't ski.
Speaker 0: But if I was going to travel to ski, then yeah, I would ski.
Speaker 0: If I'm paying this flat rate for unlimited ski, I'm going to get every ounce of ski that I can get.
Speaker 1: That would be what we would do.
Speaker 1: And it's always weird to me how most skiers, the vast majority of all skiers are not like that.
Speaker 0: They will pay the same price as me.
Speaker 1: The lift opens at like 8.30 in the morning.
Speaker 1: They'll roll in at like 11.
Speaker 1: They'll do a couple runs and then they'll go to the bar.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe they're skiing so much that they're there so many days that they don't need to, you know.
Speaker 1: True.
Speaker 1: I can't just live, well I guess I could just quit my job and go live in Colorado and ski the rest of my life.
Speaker 1: I could actually afford that if I was careful.
Speaker 1: I guess I wouldn't have healthcare.
Speaker 1: so I really would have to make sure I didn't hurt myself.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I digress.
Speaker 0: Like if I went on a trip to some foreign country and I was there for one day, I would wake up at the crack of dawn and do everything I possibly could.
Speaker 0: And if I'm there for a week, I'm going to go to sleep at a normal time.
Speaker 1: That's why I have so many photos of Istanbul at night because the first time I went there, I wasn't sure if I'd ever get back.
Speaker 1: so I was like, I'm going to spend every waking hour exploring the city.
Speaker 1: And I stayed up till like 2 in the morning wandering around every single night the whole time I was there.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, we were just at MAGFest.
Speaker 1: It was fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Cons are back.
Speaker 1: We're probably going to talk about MAGFest on Thursday because there's a lot to say.
Speaker 1: This MAGFest was, I think, the best run and best MAGFest I've ever attended.
Speaker 1: At least since they went to the Yaylord.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm always worried about MAGFest but nope.
Speaker 0: Nothing to worry about.
Speaker 1: I'd say for the first time in my life, I'm going to say that MAGFest has a higher chance of surviving than it did its previous iteration.
Speaker 1: Like MAGFest is on an upward trend in a big way.
Speaker 0: It is up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: PAX East coming up.
Speaker 1: We'll be there.
Speaker 1: Probably in Forsen doing some panels.
Speaker 1: TBD and all the details.
Speaker 1: but if you want to see us at PAX East, we will almost definitely be there doing our normal thing.
Speaker 1: What else we got going on?
Speaker 1: I guess PAX West will be that long out.
Speaker 1: Panels will open soon enough.
Speaker 1: So I guess we'll get into it.
Speaker 1: We're not going to talk about MAGFest.
Speaker 1: We're just talking about the games that were at MAGFest.
Speaker 0: Primarily in the... No.
Speaker 1: Ones that were notable or that we noticed or played in some fashion.
Speaker 0: And we're not going to talk about ones that we played in the arcade.
Speaker 0: We're not going to talk about, you know, Adam's Family Pinball Machine.
Speaker 0: It's like, come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I played a bunch of DDR.
Speaker 1: It's DDR.
Speaker 1: Okay, great.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: We're talking about a specific section of MAGFest.
Speaker 0: The MIVS.
Speaker 0: The MAGFest Indie Video Game Showcase.
Speaker 0: And this room has not a new room in MAGFest.
Speaker 0: It has been there for years at the MAGFest.
Speaker 0: But in this incarnation of MAGFest 2024, this room was what it had everything that it had the last time I was at MAGFest three or four years ago.
Speaker 0: And it had somehow enhanced greatly into like basically the best room in all of MAGFest.
Speaker 0: And what it was...
Speaker 1: Yeah, MAGFest Indie Arcade Area is basically a combination...
Speaker 0: Well, there's the Indie Arcade and there's the Indie Video Game Showcase.
Speaker 0: There's sort of like these two... It's just one room, right?
Speaker 0: But it's all the same thing to me.
Speaker 1: It is a wide margin better than the best indie setups PAX has ever had in terms of what is there, the quality, the content, the variety.
Speaker 1: MAGFest Indie Video Game Showcase is a very important thing for games and art in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Like I was blown away by what I saw there.
Speaker 1: And I feel like it's just going to get bigger every year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I think what it is is that the barrier to entry to get in there is so much lower, right?
Speaker 0: And the culture of going in there is so much different.
Speaker 0: And there's no industry presence whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And the culture has been around forever.
Speaker 1: Remember that Dodecahedron weird looking mirror game that we posted?
Speaker 0: It's still there.
Speaker 1: It is still there.
Speaker 1: That thing's been at MAGFest forever.
Speaker 1: Just like there's the metal skateboards on the janky DDR pad and there's that game where they try to make it like a DDR but on a skateboard.
Speaker 1: That's been there forever.
Speaker 1: But that area historically, nerds who had a weird idea would basically just make... Like this pile of parts or a weird box with a button and they would just interact with it.
Speaker 1: It's literally the kind of thing you'd see in a weird museum.
Speaker 1: And I credit not just MAGFest for making the space, I credit the handful of people who have been bringing their elaborate nonsense to MAGFest for the last 8 or 9 years.
Speaker 1: Just keeping this space warm for the creative explosion that has appeared this year.
Speaker 0: It's definitely a room with a demo scene vibe going on.
Speaker 0: And compared to at PAX, what you have at PAX is there's plenty of indie games there in the expo area and otherwise.
Speaker 0: But those are all supported by these mid tier publishers or the indie mega booth.
Speaker 0: There used to be the indie mini booth.
Speaker 0: This is a lot like the indie mini booth.
Speaker 0: Only no mini booth.
Speaker 0: It's like all the indie mini games get a bigger presence.
Speaker 1: But also at PAX, every game in a place like that is on Steam or available.
Speaker 1: You'll be able to buy it here.
Speaker 1: It's a mix of games that are or will be for sale through traditional channels, but also games that really just like there's one and someone just made it and there aren't more.
Speaker 1: You can't buy it on Steam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: If you're going to PAX, it's like you have a game you're trying to sell for money at some point or are already selling.
Speaker 0: Whereas here, some people just make a game, you know, the kind of game that they would throw on itch.io and not ever care to make money off of.
Speaker 0: But they'll come and set it up at Magfest to be played with no expectation of it being for sale ever or anything like that.
Speaker 1: So like to give some examples, there's one game that was there.
Speaker 1: I didn't get a chance to play it, but I watched some other people play it.
Speaker 1: And it's basically a Monty Python silly walk slash upper class twit simulator.
Speaker 1: But the control is a giant bowler hat hanging from the ceiling that you put on your head and try to balance.
Speaker 1: And that's how you control your twit.
Speaker 0: Well, two people wear the hat simultaneously, right?
Speaker 0: So it's two humans with a giant hat that is suspended from like a trestle of some kind.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And two humans strap their heads into this hat and they give you a skullcap because otherwise it'd be gross.
Speaker 0: And then you have to cooperatively use this hat to control what is happening on the screen.
Speaker 0: The line to play the game was long, but I don't feel like I needed to play it to understand what was happening when I looked at it.
Speaker 1: I saw 10 seconds of gameplay and yeah, I'm glad that was there.
Speaker 1: That's a cool thing that someone made.
Speaker 0: Now that's not a thing that anyone's going to be like selling, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're not going to buy the big hat game on Steam and then like take up half the room in your house just to put the big hat.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing you could put in like a museum as an installation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's exactly that.
Speaker 1: That's why we keep saying these are hybrids of games and installation art.
Speaker 1: And there's a movement like this.
Speaker 1: There is a movement here that is centered around Magfest.
Speaker 0: Now there are some games that could be installations, but some that you could just game.
Speaker 0: Some you can even get.
Speaker 1: Like one that I played that I'm pretty into.
Speaker 1: You know there's that weird Zelda 2 remake where someone just like redesigned the game.
Speaker 1: This one is actually going to be for sale.
Speaker 1: It is the Transylvania Adventure of Simon Quest.
Speaker 1: And it's basically the same as that Zelda 2 situation.
Speaker 1: Someone just took the essence of Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest, but re-implemented it better and avoided compromising intellectual properties so they could actually sell it.
Speaker 1: And I wasn't able to play it until about 2.30 in the morning one night when for the first time in the entire con, the church pew that they had set up in front of the coffins, the real coffins that they had in their little booth.
Speaker 1: Props to them for getting a real church pew and coffins.
Speaker 1: Did not have anyone sitting at it and I played it for like an hour and it was great.
Speaker 1: And I'm definitely going to buy it and play it for real.
Speaker 0: There was an NES game.
Speaker 0: It was like a game that someone actually made for the NES.
Speaker 0: There's a whole section actually in there of games that people have made for old consoles.
Speaker 0: That run on those old consoles.
Speaker 0: There's nothing stopping you from making a new game that's an NES game.
Speaker 0: But obviously are new and not from the olden days.
Speaker 0: And it was just this cute little game where you pick a character and your character has some kind of melee weapon, sort of like a knife.
Speaker 0: it looked like.
Speaker 0: I couldn't really tell.
Speaker 0: But at the bottom of the screen is like popcorn.
Speaker 0: Like a popcorn bag.
Speaker 0: And all these popcorn kernel guys come and try to attack you.
Speaker 0: And if you are touching them, then your health bar is decreasing.
Speaker 0: And when you're not touching them, your health bar goes up.
Speaker 0: If you have your weapon out, your health bar goes down.
Speaker 0: And if you keep your weapon sheathed, your health bar goes up.
Speaker 0: So you can't just run around holding your weapon out all the time.
Speaker 0: You have to strategically stab quickly.
Speaker 0: Like stab, stab, stab.
Speaker 0: And when you stab these guys, they pop into popcorn and fall to the bottom.
Speaker 0: Some of them are blinking.
Speaker 0: If you pop a blinking guy, then he'll turn into a popcorn and any bad guy that popcorn touches on its way down will form a chain reaction of popping.
Speaker 0: And you get a bunch of points.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: The game was surprisingly clever and interesting given the simple concept.
Speaker 0: I just kept playing it even though there wasn't more going on.
Speaker 0: I found an easy strategy to rack up a high score going back and forth off the edges of the screen Pac-Man style.
Speaker 0: Because the bad guys just come right at you.
Speaker 0: They don't have any sort of intelligence.
Speaker 0: So I'm on the left side of the screen.
Speaker 0: They all run left.
Speaker 0: I switch to the right side of the screen.
Speaker 0: They all turn around and come the other way.
Speaker 0: And then eventually I pop one guy who makes a chain reaction and sort of clear things out so it's safe.
Speaker 0: And then I just kept doing that for a long time.
Speaker 0: And then eventually the pressure did mount enough.
Speaker 0: I thought it would sort of cap out and I would be able to play forever.
Speaker 0: But eventually I did, I guess through lack of endurance or increasing number of bad guys, I died.
Speaker 0: And that was that.
Speaker 0: The person who made the game was there and we discussed and recognized that fact.
Speaker 0: And I said, "You know what you should do?
Speaker 0: You should make the popcorn go
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 0: I thought the popcorn was going to go up and create sort of a Bomberman-like pressure where the arena shrinks.
Speaker 0: But that never happened.
Speaker 0: And I was like, I was expecting this to happen and it didn't happen.
Speaker 0: And they said,
Speaker 0: "Uhhh.".
Speaker 0: And that was that.
Speaker 0: And I'm sad that I can't remember the name of the game.
Speaker 0: I took a photo of my high score and didn't take a photo of the game.
Speaker 0: Of what game it was.
Speaker 1: A game that we played together and I played several times.
Speaker 1: It actually was made by a former coworker of Emily's because they both worked at the same game studio.
Speaker 1: Nothing good can come of this.
Speaker 1: It has some big Nidhogg vibes in that it's one of those extremely tight, like knife fight in a phone booth kind of symmetric direct competition games.
Speaker 0: It's a gun fight in a phone booth to be more precise.
Speaker 1: In this case true.
Speaker 1: So basically you've got two little guys standing in a very small space and there's a hole in the ceiling.
Speaker 1: And you can punch a little bit and you can jump.
Speaker 1: and that's it.
Speaker 1: You punch each other, just knock each other back a little bit and you can jump.
Speaker 1: And after a few seconds, a gun falls.
Speaker 1: And then a few more seconds later, a bullet falls.
Speaker 1: And you can only get a point by holding the gun and the bullet at the same time and successfully shooting the other person.
Speaker 0: But you try to shoot the other person.
Speaker 0: If they're too close to you, the gun will actually be behind them and it's like you'll be holding the gun and using their shoulder as an armrest and shoot behind them.
Speaker 0: You have to be far enough away from them that the gun is gonna actually hit them.
Speaker 0: And that is not so easy.
Speaker 1: But if you're holding the gun, you can't punch.
Speaker 1: So if you're holding the gun, the other person's got the bullet, you gotta throw the gun and try to hit them.
Speaker 1: But if you mess that up, they might pick up the gun and they already have the bullet.
Speaker 1: It's a really tight game and it just forces you to win.
Speaker 1: You've got to get over the line.
Speaker 1: It's like a really hard, tight duel.
Speaker 1: It feels a lot like Nidhogg and that is a genre similar to Outlaw that I'm just a fan of in general.
Speaker 1: I love that genre.
Speaker 1: But the cool thing is, they had it set up in an arcade machine and part of what has helped this creative explosion is just in the last few years, there are multiple companies and multiple avenues to very easily build, buy, or otherwise craft full-size arcade machines that have arbitrary stuff inside of them.
Speaker 1: Like it's got the barrier entrance.
Speaker 0: All you really gotta do is get some wood and if you have woodworking, you can make the cabinet.
Speaker 0: And then inside the cabinet, all you need to put is a Raspberry Pi and a screen and a power cable.
Speaker 0: And then controls, you can just buy joysticks and buttons anywhere.
Speaker 0: And there you go, you got yourself an arcade cabinet decorated how you would.
Speaker 1: There was a Black Emperor and I did get to play Black Emperor.
Speaker 0: It was the Black Emperor.
Speaker 0: I gotta say Black Emperor, now having played it, if you don't know, it was the Omega-Thon finale at PAX West.
Speaker 0: The controls on it are extremely tight and good.
Speaker 0: Perfect, basically.
Speaker 0: It is not actually a hard game at all, control-wise.
Speaker 0: You can perfectly control that bicycle.
Speaker 0: I got the hang of it in like two seconds, motorcycle.
Speaker 0: The only challenge in that game, it is the challenge of memorization because the things come at you so fast that no human could react to most of the changes.
Speaker 0: Because when sand comes at you, you have to hit the throttle harder.
Speaker 0: And when the road turns, you have to turn and it comes at you so fast, you can't possibly react fast enough to not die no matter where you position yourself on the screen.
Speaker 0: So you have to just memorize what's coming up next because it is set in stone, at least until it changes.
Speaker 1: It's the same game as Kaboom for the most part, just with a radically different style.
Speaker 0: Effectively speaking, yes.
Speaker 0: It's Kaboom, but there's also a button you have to regulate.
Speaker 0: Kaboom, you only have to regulate the wheel.
Speaker 1: Speaking of memorization, so Emily and I played a game called Bunny Beats by Studio Tapioca.
Speaker 0: Oh, I saw that one.
Speaker 1: It's got really cute art, but... It's a rhythm game.
Speaker 1: It's a rhythm game, but it's a rhythm game that doesn't fuck around.
Speaker 1: We played it on Easy.
Speaker 1: It is hard.
Speaker 1: I appreciate it in that it is a rhythm game that someone who is good at music and understands rhythm and possibly is a percussionist would love, but someone who does not have rhythm and is not good at music could not play it.
Speaker 1: It basically is a bunch of bunnies.
Speaker 1: They're making mochis, so they're hammering the mochi.
Speaker 1: It's really cute and there's a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: And they're all playing basically a different part of what is a percussion song.
Speaker 1: And the way the game works, it'll show you one of the bunnies will be highlighted, and you have to pay attention to just that bunny and see what part the bunny is playing, memorize it and learn it, having heard it only once.
Speaker 1: And then, in the next stanza of the music, play that bunny's part without any notes or any prompts or any help.
Speaker 0: Yep, this is the middle challenge, right?
Speaker 0: Because you think, "Oh, I could be a percussionist.
Speaker 0: It's so easy,
Speaker 0: right?".
Speaker 0: Some people cannot keep a beat or a rhythm whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I, at least, believe that I can keep a beat or a rhythm.
Speaker 1: The problem is... I've seen you play DDR.
Speaker 1: You definitely can keep a beat or a rhythm, and you can definitely follow instructions on a screen of when to step where.
Speaker 0: I can keep exactly one beat, a rhythm, right?
Speaker 0: At a time, right?
Speaker 0: I can be like, you know, one, two, one, two, one, two, right?
Speaker 0: To be an actual drummer, you have to be able to have one hand...
Speaker 1: Polyrhythm, three on one hand, four on the other hand simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Right, you have to have one hand doing one rhythm and the other hand doing a completely different rhythm, right?
Speaker 0: Not even one hand going one, two, one, two, and the other hand going one, two, three, four, where they're sort of sharing, right?
Speaker 0: That's still the same rhythm.
Speaker 0: We're talking about completely different.
Speaker 0: One hand is going like...
Speaker 1: But it's not like most rhythm games that even have memorization components where it shows you the rhythm, or it shows you the thing, and then you do the thing, and it's kind of synthetic.
Speaker 1: This is more like you're going to hear someone play something, and then you've got to play the same thing in context, and it's a skill that musicians have.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone else has that skill.
Speaker 0: Right, this is in this sort of middle area.
Speaker 0: It's not asking you to do the full challenge of two simultaneous different rhythms, but it is asking you to do a rhythm while other rhythms are in your ears that aren't the one you're going to play, right?
Speaker 0: And the one you are going to play is not being hinted at, right, while you are playing it visually.
Speaker 0: You have to have memorized it from having heard it sort of like Simon, but it's like if you were four Simons, and you had to reproduce just one of the Simons, and the other four were beeping, the other ones were beeping away at you, right?
Speaker 0: At the same time, it's like that's what this game is.
Speaker 0: Pretty clever.
Speaker 1: But the reason why it's not just impossible is that you're playing the rhythm in the context of a legitimate real song, so it'd be like someone who's an artist- Your rhythm does fit with the other ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and picking up on how it fits and what it's doing, which, again, I don't think anyone who is not a musician is capable of.
Speaker 1: That's the challenge.
Speaker 0: Another game that I saw and played, which is available on itch.io at blairzang.itch.io/bbb, is called Bamboom Blade.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's real good.
Speaker 0: This is real simple.
Speaker 0: So basically, it's trying to simulate, you know, kung fu movie wuxia sword fight, you know, situations, sort of like Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon style.
Speaker 0: There are two very tall bamboo trunks, and on each trunk, there is a warrior person with a sword and nothing else, and they're holding on to that bamboo trunk.
Speaker 0: And the controls are very simple.
Speaker 0: It's twin stick.
Speaker 0: The left stick allows you to move up and down the trunk.
Speaker 0: And the second stick- well, that same- the left stick also, if you move left or right, will allow you to bend the bamboo trunk to the left or right, basically shifting your weight.
Speaker 0: So you can whip yourself around on this trunk like,
Speaker 0: "Ooh-wee!".
Speaker 0: It's a 2D game.
Speaker 0: The right stick only controls your sword.
Speaker 0: If it aims up, you'll hold your sword in the sky.
Speaker 0: If you aim it down, you'll put your sword down.
Speaker 0: If you spin the stick around in a circle, you'll spin your stick- sword around like a, you know, whirlwind, like a- like a fan that's gonna chew up something that gets thrown into it, right?
Speaker 0: And so, there is someone else on the other stick with the same controls, and you are trying to stab them to death without being stabbed to death.
Speaker 0: The rules of this game are quite fascinating in that I found it wasn't quite Bushido Blade, where any touch of the sword kills someone.
Speaker 0: It's very smart with locations and physics and speed.
Speaker 0: Like, for example, in one game, I came together with my opponent, my sword went right into their leg.
Speaker 0: Like, right into it, and their blood was coming out.
Speaker 0: Gary- I knew I hit him.
Speaker 0: Their knee hit me in the head, and I died.
Speaker 0: The sword did not touch me.
Speaker 0: So, that's the kind of game it is.
Speaker 0: If you want to have a two-player fighting game that has a really low barrier to entry, but really sort of high skill cap and possibilities, it's obviously not gonna take you as high as an actual fighting game, like a Street Fighter kind of situation, but you can get a lot of play out of this one.
Speaker 0: And I think you can even get more play out of this than, like, a dive kick.
Speaker 0: So, I appreciated it very much.
Speaker 0: I don't even think they're asking any money.
Speaker 0: One that stood out- Yeah, I pushed download, and it didn't even ask me for money.
Speaker 0: It just, like, starts downloading.
Speaker 1: We'll get in on that.
Speaker 1: That had to be in Outlaw 2 for us, Nidhogg 2.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to Outlaw, just a one-on-one, completely symmetric situation.
Speaker 1: So, I forget the exact title of this game, but it's, like, Bad Art Forgeries.
Speaker 1: It was a really cute little thing.
Speaker 1: It was just set up.
Speaker 1: And basically, you get in the middle of the screen, there's a pixel representation of a famous painting.
Speaker 1: And it's a versus art forgery game.
Speaker 1: You have a very limited amount of time to, with a mouse and a very coarse MS paint set of brushes, recreate that painting as fast as possible.
Speaker 1: The winner is whoever gets the most pixels correct by the end of the timer.
Speaker 1: I won.
Speaker 1: I beat Emily.
Speaker 1: Our paintings look very different from each other.
Speaker 1: My percentage was 62.3.
Speaker 1: I got 62.3% of the pixels correct.
Speaker 1: And Emily got 61.92% of the pixels correct.
Speaker 0: It's literally counting how many pixels are the correct color.
Speaker 0: That's all the game is.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: It is real fun, and it's a really clever idea.
Speaker 0: Okay, the absolute best game that I saw that I don't want to miss is a game called QuestFast, a customer copy adventure.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, that was one of the most impressive things in that whole space.
Speaker 0: It is the best one.
Speaker 0: So, this game, game-wise, is just an adventure game, right?
Speaker 0: Like a text adventure, or a Queen's Quest, or a Monkey Island, or a Shadow Gate, right?
Speaker 0: Where it's like, look at the room, go north, use this item on that thing.
Speaker 0: That's the game.
Speaker 0: There's nothing special about it in that regard.
Speaker 0: It's basically a text adventure where you're going to make breakfast, right?
Speaker 0: Get eggs, get milk, crack eggs into bowl, turn on stove, put eggs in pan- You're trying to make breakfast.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game.
Speaker 0: Nothing else to it, right?
Speaker 0: What makes this game special is the interface for the game.
Speaker 0: They created an entire cash register with a 10-key numpad, a little LCD display with two rows of text, two receipt printers, and a barcode scanner, as well as some markers and a little bulletin board you can use.
Speaker 0: And what happens is there's one receipt printer that is the main one, and that one is basically printing this never-ending long receipt.
Speaker 0: And that never-ending long receipt is actually the main output of the game.
Speaker 0: It says, like, if you tell it, "Look at the plate," then it prints, and you'll see the plate, and you'll see a description of the plate, and it confirms, "The action you chose was to look at plate.
Speaker 0: Here's what you
Speaker 0: saw.".
Speaker 0: And that's the output, right?
Speaker 0: There's also a side receipt printer.
Speaker 0: Whenever you acquire an item, it prints out a tiny little receipt and cuts it, and you get a little slip of paper that has that item and also a barcode on it that represents that item.
Speaker 0: There's also, I think, like, seven barcodes that are, like, always just there.
Speaker 0: Like, those are for the main actions, like, you know, look, take, eat, et cetera.
Speaker 0: So you would scan on the look barcode, which is always there, and scan the plate, the little tiny receipt you're holding, and that's how you look at the plate.
Speaker 0: You scan -- everything you do in this game is always scanning two barcodes.
Speaker 0: Scan an action, and then scan a thing.
Speaker 0: Scan an action, scan a thing.
Speaker 0: That's all the input for the game.
Speaker 0: And the most genius thing is that on that main, the main receipt printer, the big long one that's going infinitely, that has all the output from the game, when it prints the room you're in, right?
Speaker 0: It actually prints out a little picture of the room you're in.
Speaker 0: And if you look closely at it, you'll notice all the items in the room have barcodes on them.
Speaker 0: So it's like when you open the fridge, you'll see there's, like, eggs in the fridge, and it's a picture of eggs, but the picture of the egg carton is filled in with a barcode.
Speaker 0: So you click "look" -- well, you click, you scan the look barcode, and then you go over to the big receipt, the mega long one, and you scan the eggs in there, right?
Speaker 0: And it's like, "Ah, yes, you see a carton of
Speaker 0: eggs.".
Speaker 0: And then you scan "take eggs," and then the tiny receipt printer prints out a little receipt with the eggs.
Speaker 0: And so that way, you can go to a different room and still have the egg barcode available now to do something else with.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game, but what shocked me the most, not only did they have this genius input system for a basic adventure game, but that it was functional and responsive and fast.
Speaker 0: Like, you scanned, and it printed out quickly in shocking resolution.
Speaker 0: It didn't run out of paper, it didn't run out of ink, maybe I just got to it when it was working well, but it was working so well.
Speaker 0: Like, it was probably might even be faster than Shadowgate on the NES, right?
Speaker 0: It's like beep beep, right?
Speaker 0: You were going fast in this game.
Speaker 0: It was an impressive game.
Speaker 1: Just what an installation.
Speaker 1: that set up for us.
Speaker 0: It was made by Team Registration at WPI IMGD Questfast, designed and developed by Eddie, Garrett, Xian, Zihang Chen, and Lexi McFann in just over a week.
Speaker 0: Took them over a week to make this.
Speaker 0: Some genius kids over there at WPI.
Speaker 1: So, I think we've gone on long enough, but suffice it to say, that was only a small sampling.
Speaker 0: I got more.
Speaker 0: There were genius things happening.
Speaker 1: I mean, I was looking at the website, and there were games I see on the website that I did not notice, despite trying to explore that area.
Speaker 0: I know that all of these I saw, but not all of them were genius.
Speaker 1: I didn't even get to talk about the book ritual, or Hernah, or Tug of Peace, which I loved.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to talk about Dr.
Speaker 1: Garf, who I fucked.
Speaker 1: Or South Scrimshaw text adventure with a giant whale.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there was just so much going on in that room.
Speaker 0: That room was at previous MAGFest, but it was twice or at least twice as stacked as it was previously.
Speaker 0: I could have spent way more hours in just that one room.
Speaker 1: It was notable how expanded and amazing that room was.
Speaker 1: I cannot praise it enough.
Speaker 1: Good job, MAGFest.
Speaker 1: I think Mibs is going to grow and be a very, very critical part of that con forever.
Speaker 0: The way I see it is, if you look at anime cons, they got their dealer's room, and then they got their artist alley, which is really just cheap dealer's room.
Speaker 1: This is more like installation alley.
Speaker 0: Right, but that's only half of it.
Speaker 0: The other half of it is just booths.
Speaker 0: Normal old booths, not installations.
Speaker 0: Only the arcade part is installations.
Speaker 0: But it's like if there was a second PAX expo hall.
Speaker 0: that was super low rent, and you couldn't get in there.
Speaker 0: if you were a real company, it wouldn't let you.
Speaker 0: But it's just like the cost to get in there was so low, and the culture of MAGFest is being what it is.
Speaker 1: Speaking of the cost to get in there, do you know how that room actually works?
Speaker 0: Do you have to apply?
Speaker 1: No, so all the people who want to put something in that room, they submit a video of uninterrupted gameplay between 30 seconds and 2 minutes.
Speaker 1: The judges watch the video and decide if your game is accepted, you are given the space, you are given power and tables, you are given free badges, and you are given the right to buy a hotel room in the Gaylord.
Speaker 0: Oh, that makes me want to make a game just to get the hotel room.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCoup.com for show notes, discussion, links, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of Geek Nights are... One of the things that they had set up in the museum was a regular-ass rotary telephone hooked up to a fake, like, phone exchange so you could dial it and use it.
Speaker 1: And that was just there in the museum.
Speaker 1: And I watch.
Speaker 1: I walk in and I see it and I'm thinking, "That's
Speaker 1: funny.".
Speaker 1: I watched a dad walk up with what looked like his daughter, and his daughter's like, "What's
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "That's a
Speaker 1: phone.".
Speaker 1: And the kid's like, "No, it
Speaker 1: isn't.".
Speaker 1: And there was a whole exchange, and I was slowly crumbling to dust the entire time.
Speaker 1: So on that note, I leave you... tonight... with...